ZHENGYANG HUANG

- email: zhuang0buo@outlook.com - phone: +1 757-719-6047

- project highlights: https://zhengyang-huang.me/Project-Highlights.pdf

- website: https://zhengyang-huang.me/

- LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/zhengyang-huang/

Zhengyang is a new media artist working in interactive media with web and game engine as well as 3D/2D graphics, motion effects, and videography. He's been doing both collaborative and self-initiated projects for years and gained versatile experiences in aesthetics, software and skills spanning from artistic, educational to commercial fields.

EDUCATION

UCLA - MFA, Design | Media Arts - Los Angeles, CA College of William and Mary - BA, Studio Arts - 3D - Williamsburg, VA June 2021 May 2019

SKILL

- Web and Game Interactives: HTML, Javascript, CSS, Jquery, Wordpress, Webpack, Unity3D, Unity C#, Processing, Arduino, Git, Github;
- 3D/2D Graphics: Autodesk Maya, VR video, Reality Capture, RunwayML, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe InDesign, Figma;
- Videography and Motion Graphics: Adobe
 AfterEffects, Adobe Premiere Pro, Adobe Audition,
 Audacity;
- Soft Skills: Concept building, Communication Skill, Teamwork, Problem-Solving Ability, Flexibility, Time Management;

WORK EXPERIENCE

Videographer / Visual Designer - Global Talent Link · Contract

August 2021 - Present

- Creating a marketing video with animated assets, motion effects, company footages;
- Designed landing page's responsive header with Lottie SVG animation and development in HTML, CSS, Javascript;
- Revamping company website with illustrations and prototypes;
- Illustrated community flyer to be posted both in print and online, with QR code tracking included for marketing purpose;

Lecturer - UCLA - Los Angeles, CA

June 2021 - August 2021

- Taught *DESMA 24 Motion* (https://classes.dma.ucla.edu/Summer21/24/), a course in theory and practice of motion graphics including video making and editing, 3D modeling and animation, as well as generated images;
- Led learning sessions and made tutorials for Autodesk Maya, Adobe After Effects, Premiere Pro, and RunwayML;
- Led lectures, discussions, screenings, critiques to expand knowledge and develop critical thinking on moving images;

Teaching assistant - UCLA - Los Angeles, CA

October 2019 - June 2021

- Led discussion sessions to expand course materials and have more discussions on media art history and practice;
- Designed and created websites to manage and share materials and resources as well as showcasing student work;
- Assisted instructors in and out of class, coordinated meetings, supported students on projects and assignments;
- List of courses:
 - o 09/2019 12/2019 Media Arts Introduction
 - o 01/2020 03/2020 Motion (https://classes.dma.ucla.edu/Winter20/24/)
 - o 09/2020 12/2020 Special Topics: Cultural Appropriation With Machine Learning
 - o 09/2020 12/2020 Design Culture
 - o 01/2021 03/2021 Motion
 - o 03/2021 06/2021 Video (https://classes.dma.ucla.edu/Spring21/153/)

EXHIBITION

2021

- *Air, Water, Fire*, SLSA 2021 (Society for Literature, Science, and The Arts,), Penny W. Stamps School of Art & Design at the University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, https://stamps.umich.edu/events/slsa-exhibit, 10/2021
- Air, Water, Fire, in group show The Last Online Show, D|MA MFA show, http://projects.dma.ucla.edu/exhibitions/mfa2021/2020/10/13/zhengyang/, 05/2021
- Air, solo show in collaboration, online, D|MA, 02/2021

2020

- Share Screen, D|MA Fall Preview Show, https://projects.dma.ucla.edu/exhibitions/sharescreen/, 10/2020
 - Besides showing work, I also developed and designed the landing page of the exhibition website

2019

- Image at Surface, solo show at Linda Matney Gallery, Williamsburg VA, 04/2019
- Capstone Show, group show at Williamsburg Contemporary Art Center, Williamsburg VA, 02/2019
- A Sense of Occasion, group show at Andrews Gallery, Williamsburg VA, 05/2019
 2018
- Transposition: Asian Cultures, group show at Linda Matney Gallery, Williamsburg VA, 02/2018

PUBLICATION

- Image at Surface, Artsy, 2019
- Transparency, Acropolis Art Journal, 2017
- Solidarity, Acropolis Art Journal, 2017
- Chaos // Disorder, Acropolis Art Journal, 2016

GRANTS AND AWARDS

2021

- Clifton Webb Scholarship, School of Arts & Architecture, UCLA, 01/2021 06/2021
- Dr. Hyuman Eugene Oxman & Frieda Dreyer Oxman Fellowship Fund, School of Arts & Architecture, UCLA, 01/2021
 06/2021

2020

- Dean's Graduate Scholarship, D|MA, School of Arts & Architecture, UCLA, 09/2020 06/2021
- Alumni Association Award, College of William and Mary, 06/2019

2018

- Honors Research Project Fellowship, College of William and Mary, 08/2018 05/2019
- The Joseph Palin Thorley Memorial Scholarship for the Study of Art, College of William and Mary
- Initiated as a member of Phi Beta Kappa, Alpha of Virginia at the College of William and Mary, 12/05/2018 2017
- The Joseph Palin Thorley Memorial Scholarship for the Study of Art, College of William and Mary
- Roy R. Charles Grant for Semester Independent Study, College of William and Mary